Contact

christina.rodriguez061@gmai l.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ christinarodriguez (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Nursing

Hospitals

Languages

Spanish

Certifications

Critical Care Registered Nurse (Adult) (CCRN-A)

MRC Core Competencies Training, Institute for Disaster and Emergency Preparedness

Basic Life Support (BLS) for Healthcare Providers

Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Registered Nurse

Christina Rodriguez

Critical Care RN at Mercy Hospital (BSN, RN, CCRN)

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Summary

Critical care registered nurse with 5 years experience as a specialized CCRN working in the CVICU at Mercy Hospital. Focused, dedicated and versatile always aspiring to practice, acquire, and improve new skills to promote health across the nursing care continuum. Possesses strong practical nursing experience within multi-disciplinary healthcare environments.

A proactive professional adopting a motivated and positive approach to all tasks, with a commitment to safeguarding the medical needs, comfort, and emotional well being of all patients. Excellent interpersonal and communication skills with the ability to adapt to any situation and prioritize tasks efficiently and effectively.

Key assets are strong critical thinking skills, the ability to communicate with patients, families and healthcare team members at all levels and a natural facility to work under pressure. Open and welcome to any opportunity that will enhance development of knowledge and professional growth across a range of nursing procedures/practices that encompass all aspects of critical care.

Strong areas of skill:

- Quickly identifying critical changes in patient condition in a fast paced environment and implementing the proper intervention and treatment required in collaboration with other healthcare team members
- Excellent time management skills while implementing nursing actions and evaluating patient response
- Recovering post-op open heart patients; skilled training with
 4+ years experience caring for patients on CRRT, LVADs, IABP,
 ECMO; initiating and completing induced hypothermia protocol for
 Code Ice patients
- Communicating effectively with a diverse patient population (bilingual in written and spoken Spanish)

Experience

HCA East Florida Division
5 years 11 months

CVICU Nurse (BSN, RN, CCRN)

January 2015 - Present (5 years 6 months)

Miami, Florida

Critical Care Registered Nurse August 2014 - Present (5 years 11 months) Miami, Florida

Looking to develop professional growth within a dynamic healthcare environment.

Ready to apply assessment, technical skills, communication, critical thinking, interpersonal skills, planning, intervention, evaluation, flexibility, organizational skills, professional accountability, leadership and service.

Jackson Health System 10 months

Nursing - Clinical January 2014 - May 2014 (5 months)

Ryder Trauma Unit 3A - 1611 NW 12th Ave, Miami, FL 33136

Independent nursing skills – in charge of full pt. shift assignments. Delivering proper, efficient and safe pt. care. Implementing the nursing process with application of leadership skills and evidence-based research. HIPAA compliant. After receiving report, triaging assignments by degree of urgency/illness for quality time management. Confirming medication orders by ensuring correct dose, route, frequency, and nursing considerations. Completing head-to-toe and focused nursing assessments, establishing nursing diagnoses, interventions, and goals. Monitoring for sudden decline in condition and recognizing normal vs. abnormal lab values. Critical thinking skills to provide recommendations for possible changes in pt. care to improve health status if goals are not met. Documenting in EMR. Initiating proper precautions, as per protocol. Clinical procedures - properly maintaining sterile field, preventing inadvertent breaks in sterile or clean technique. Pt. advocate.

Nursing - Clinical August 2013 - December 2013 (5 months) Transplant Unit - 1611 NW 12th Ave, Miami, FL 33136 Developing independent nursing skills, along with providing proper, efficient and safe patient care. Triaging pt. assignments and implementing great time management skills. Confirming medication orders prior to administration with the appropriate knowledge concerning the correct dose, route, frequency, and nursing considerations. Head-to-toe and and focused patient assessments, establishing nursing diagnoses, interventions, and goals. Documenting patient information in their EMR. Developing care plan individualized to every pt. Providing discharge teaching. HIPAA compliant.

Nursing - Clinical August 2013 - October 2013 (3 months) Holtz Children's Hospital - 1611 NW 12th Ave, Miami, FL 33136

Incorporating effective pt. and family teaching while delivering independent pt. care with confidence. Establishing a care plan while incorporating the nursing process to focus on pt. needs. Receiving report and triaging each pt. by degree of urgency/illness. Completing head-to-toe and focused assessments. Confirming medication orders prior to administration with ensuring correct dose, route, frequency, and nursing considerations. Reviewing any new changes in pt. status/condition and reviewing recent lab work or diagnostic exams performed. Making proper preparations if pt. scheduled to be transferred off of the floor. Documenting pt. information in EMR in a timely and efficient manner. Completing all assigned tasks and pt. orders on time with dedication and professionalism.

Agape Family Services, LLC Nursing - Clinical January 2014 - March 2014 (3 months)

Counseling and Mental Health Facility - 9715 SW 161st St, Miami, FL 33157

Incorporating different forms of therapeutic communication with the women in the facility suffering from psychiatric illness and substance abuse that were involuntarily admitted. I was responsible for coordinating and running therapy sessions in both group and individual settings, where I strengthened by therapeutic communication skills during discussions of a variety of topics with them, such as: teaching skills on how to integrate a healthy diet and lifestyle while in the facility; understanding how to identify and manage extrapyramidal symptoms caused by the medications they were taking; encouraging the women to discuss individual strengths and goals once they leave the facility; help the women work on their interpersonal skills and tips on how to avoid any triggers that they could identify which might contribute to an impulsive response. I was also responsible for maintaining a safe environment and delegating responsibilities to members during group therapy sessions.

Palmetto Health Nursing - Clinical October 2013 - December 2013 (3 months)

Labor & Delivery/Postpartum Care - 2001 W 68 Street, Hialeah, FL#

During this rotation, my duties were more focused on gaining experience and knowledge while observing cesarean sections be performed, as well as natural childbirth. I was responsible for strengthening my skills on the proper methods of the surgical scrub, gown, and glove procedure. My duties also consisted of developing teaching plans for the postpartum mothers on topics such as: how to successfully begin breastfeeding newborns and proper positioning; implementing evidence-based research to inform the mothers on vaccinations and clear up any misconceptions.

Baptist Health South Florida
Nursing - Clinical
January 2013 - May 2013 (5 months)
Cardiac & Vascular Institute - 8900 N Kendall Dr, Miami, FL 33176

Duties included strengthening my nursing skills through observing and learning from my nurse preceptors/mentors. I was assigned to one nurse and able to work side by side with them during their shift. Gathered hands on knowledge and experience concerning how to triage patient assignments after receiving shift report and developing my friendly bedside manner. Managing patient care, focused on health promotion and maintenance. Administering bed baths. Assisting in frequent patient turning for those unable to ambulate. Helping to feed the patients on aspiration precautions during meal times. Obtaining vital signs and performing glucose finger stick tests. Administering medications with the nurse and being responsible for identifying all medications being given and listing any and all nursing considerations. Observing/learning how to properly document in the patients EMR. Establishing how to develop a proper time management routine and implementing it during every shift.

Doctor's Family Clinic
Medical Assistant
June 2004 - January 2012 (7 years 8 months)
4881 Palm Beach Blvd, Fort Myers, FL 33905

Performing proper disposal of bio hazardous waste in accordance to appropriate procedures. Sterilization and maintenance of surgical instruments. Taking pt. vitals. Documenting vital signs and chief complaint of pt. Performing EKG analyses and interpreting results. Running bone density scans. Performing ear lavages. Conducting spirometry testing. Preparing/overseeing

inhalation therapy devices. Venipuncture/Phlebotomy - collection of diagnostic blood specimen. Operating centrifuge system for lab specimens. Preparing/ running diagnostic codes for lab sample pick-up. Administering ordered IM, SUBQ, and intradermal injections. Assisting the physician in minimally invasive surgical procedures - preparing surgical tray with respect to sterile area. Assisting in the removal of benign/malignant skin biopsies. Assisting in GYN exams and sending out the proper Dx lab order codes. Removal of sutures. Conducting immigration physical exams – gathering and documenting pt. history.

Education

University of Miami- School of Nursing and Health Studies
Bachelor's Degree, RN, BSN - Accelerated Nursing Program · (2013 - 2014)

Florida Gulf Coast University
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Psychology (2007 - 2012)